# WILL WEIMING ZHUANG



# Skill Summary

More than 15 years of experience in system technology research and development and architecture design, and familiar with key technologies in the fields of **distributed systems**, **financial technology**, **design thinking**, **process design and optimization**. Early promoter and open source contributor of **blockchain**, **mobile**, **workflow**, **cloud** and other technologies. Published papers and speeches in academic journals and conferences, and applied for more than ten patents. Responsible for corporate IT R&D **strategic planning**, **digital transformation**, **data security**, **contracts**, **R&D budget**, **IT governance**, **vendors**, **teams** and other management work.

# **Experiences**

### HSBC / Dec 2021 / Lead Engineer

Lab Engineering Lead, implement new technology into Bank, like CBDC, web 3.0, AI, mobile, regulatory technology, cloud, etc.. Lead and drive the innovation into business from 0 to 1, make things happen. Also lead related strategic planning / digital transformation / team leadership / vendor development / data security / IT governance / business change management.

Happening external public projects from 0 to 1 - 1) e-HKD; 2) NFT.

### <u>Dalian Commodity Exchange</u> / Jul 2020 ~ Dec 2021 / Lead Architect

DCE Leader & Designer & Principle programmer on blockchain & DApp & Alliance governance in Commodity trading. Successfully 1) lead the blockchain products of Dalian Commodity Exchange go live, and 2) lead the team to pass the sixth batch of Trusted Blockchain Tests by the Institute of Information and Communications Technology. Also lead the related strategic planning / budgeting / contract /digital transformation / team leadership / vendor management. Based on this blockchain product, led Bank of Communications and COFCO implemented the blockchain warehouse receipt pledge financing project, which is currently operating smoothly.

#### • Shanghai Insurance Exchange / Apr 2017 ~ Jun 2020 / Technical Lead

SHIE Blockchain principal Architecture, core programmer. Leader of SHIEChain pass the test of CAICT (Community Associations Institute - Connecticut Chapter).

As Lead of Blockchain team, responsible for overall direction and execution, innovate insurance companies, design solution and lead team to deliver projects.

As blockchain solutions designer and principle programmer of Consortium of reinsurance, Digital insurance policy, Digital customer identification across insurance, insurance Policy pledge, insurance asset of supplementary pension, etc.

Innovated consortium Blockchain methodology. As team lead, Won the first prize of Shanghai Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition 2018.

Protagonist of SHIE Chain News I, SHIE Chain News II

### • Ant Financial / Jul 2016 ~ Mar 2017 / Blockchain Expert

I am an architecture & designer, principle coder of Ant Chain platform, and developed application of charitable donations go live. I am Consensus algorithm designer and programmer. Also, <u>I am the representative speaker of Ant Financial on Blockchain Conference holding by MIIT</u>.

#### • IBM / May 2007 ~ Jul 2016 / Innovation consultant, Senior Architect

In Year 2016, in IBM GBS Innovation center, I am the first blockchain developer and consultant. I initiated pilot blockchain POC for ICBC (Industrial and Commercial bank of China), MVP for Rural Credit Banks Funds Clearing Center and Postal Savings Bank of China, provided blockchain training for Bank of China (Hong Kong).

In Year 2015, in IBM Innovation center, responsible for coach and development of IBM mobile and cloud garage, the developer and designer of pilot mobile MVPs for ICBC and BL.COM.

In IBM, as a project manager, developer and consultant, worked on e-commerce, business process management, E-mail and accounting projects.

Volunteer of IBM CSC Program, 2010.10, Ghana Team 5.

## **Education**

Dalian Maritime University, Obtained Mater and Bachelor

# **Accomplishments**

#### Applied patents (total 12)

- Method and device for processing service request (2017 CN TW, 2018 PL WO ES MX RU KR BR JP CA AU EP, 2019 PH US)
- Method, apparatus, and system for blockchain consensus (2017 CN TW, 2018 US KR RU SG MX JP WO CA BR AU EP, 2019 ZA PH AU, 2020 US, 2021 US)
- Asynchronous multiparty data interaction method based on block chain system and storage medium (CN)
- Block chain common recognition method based on Raft algorithm (CN)
- Method and system for replacing leader of block chain network
- Architecture design and implementation of block chain hot upgrading
- Device, method and system for realizing block chain, and medium,
- o <u>Insurance underwriting method and system and computer storage medium</u>, etc.

### Publications

- Research on Blockchain Application in Insurance Industry
- <u>Blockchain Practical Application Methodology in Small and Middle Insurance Enterprise on</u>
   <u>"Modern Bankers"</u>

#### Credential

- o Credential of Dalian 2020 urban development is in short supply of talents
- PMP Credential (2010-2013), PMP@ #: 1465859
- Obtaining IREB CPRE Credential from 2012
- IBM certificated Experienced Level in IT Application Consulting & Cross Industry specializations,
  2014

• Secure Code Warrior certification, orange belt, highest level, 2022

#### Honor & Award

- First Prize of Outstanding Research Achievements in the Reform and Development of Shanghai's
  Financial Industry 2018-2019
- Leader of team won the first prize of 2018 Shanghai Blockchain Innovation Competition
- Leader of team pass the blockchain function and performance test by China Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, 2018, 2021